Charlie Rick

Curriculum Vitae

www.charick.co.uk

M 07525 788 443 E charick@me.com A 33 Bedford Road, Laindon, Essex SS15 6PG

I'm from a design background with 5 years of experience. I'm now furthering my career by branching out into Web Development. I've completed a self-funded coding boot camp and am looking for a Junior Developer role. My aim is to constantly evolve as a developer.

Experience

S6 Design & Print Designer/IT Admin

May 2016 - June 2018

- Set up and maintenance of hardware and network for an industrial printing operation.
- Project management of commercial projects.
- Research & analysis of new software and hardware to improve business productivity.
- Chose and assembled PC components to create machines that met performance requirements.
- Working collaboratively with colleagues to overcome challenges.
- Communication with high profile clients.
- Build and upkeep of company websites, created CMS for easy blog updates.
- Design of branding, graphics and marketing materials.
- Troubleshooting issues that arose with hardware/software. Competent with Windows/Mac OS, Adobe CC Apps, RIP Software and wide format printer installations/repairs.

Essex Business & Leisure Designer

August 2013 - April 2016

- Responsible for the design, production & distribution of 55,000 publications each month.
- Effective planning & organisation to ensure all publications were finalised before deadlines.
- Interpersonal skills for building rapport with clients, forming professional relationships.
- Problem solving design, software and production challenges.

Education

Just IT

June 2018 - August 2018

Self-funded intensive coding boot camp where I learned coding fundamentals as well as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API usage, C#, ASP.NET, MVC Concepts and SQL.

Woodlands School, Basildon GCSE & Diploma

September 2008 - July 2013

English Literature $B \mid$ English Language $C \mid$ Maths $B \mid$ Biology $C \mid$ Chemistry $C \mid$ Physics $C \mid$ Geography $C \mid$ German $C \mid$ Music $B \mid$ IT Level 2 Credit (Equivalent to two $B \mid$ grade GCSEs)

Skills	Core skills are in Bold	Interests
--------	--------------------------------	-----------

HTML React Computing From a very young age, I've had a keen interest in IT. I've always been an avid gamer & enjoyed learning more about hardware and new software.

JavaScript ASP.NET

Music I'm passionate about live music, I frequently

jQuery

SQL

Music I'm passionate about live music, I frequently go to gigs. I'm also a guitarist in a band with my friends,

Adobe CC Apps

Music I'm passionate about live music, I frequently go to gigs. I'm also a guitarist in a band with my friends,

regularly playing gigs across London.